hello guys so my name is krushnayak and
welcome to my YouTube channel so guys uh
we will continue the end-to-end machine
learning project series now uh you know
till now I have uploaded nine tutorials
uh I have to probably rename this uh
Project Playlist not seven days but
it'll be more now because since I'm
going to add ml Ops cicd pipeline GitHub
action so everything will get added
right so uh in the last tutorial we had
actually done the deployment in AWS
Beanstalk now in this video we will
consider a project and we'll try to
deploy that in the Azure but before I go
ahead I really want to give a quick
shout out to one of the subscriber his
name is utkarsh okay so utkarsh guy quad
so what he has done is that after
learning from this entire project right
now uh he has actually created a new
project with respect to a new data set
and the data set over here that he's
specifically using and the problem
statement is he's using is something
called as gemstone price prediction now
in this gemstone price is prediction we
are going to predict the price of the
gemstone based on features like ID carat
cut color Clarity depth table everything
right and we have to probably give the
uh you know find out the price so this
was probably from a kaggle competition
over here you can probably see this
kaggle uh entire information is given
about this data set amazingly
implemented solution most of the
techniques that he has used inside the
source folder he has basically used the
same project structure same folder
structure so if you are able to follow
this entire playlist he has basically
followed this playlist and he has
created all these things see data
transformation everything like how we
specifically used he has just used
different different features and he has
followed the same pattern okay so a good
amazing uh shout out to utkarsh for
doing this amazing work and sharing it
with the entire audience he had posted
in the LinkedIn so I thought of why not
representing this particular project I
will take this project now and I'll
deploy that in Azure again guys I'm
clearly saying the credit goes to
utkarsh for this project okay my project
is also there like which I had actually
developed it is almost similar but here
now what we are going to do we are going
to take this project and we are going to
do the deployment in Azure okay so
quickly if you go and see in the vs code
this is how the project structure looks
like you know you have your notebook
files EDM model training everything is
here and he is really really represented
written all the nodes very much cleanly
so you can definitely refer this okay ah
but if you want to implement it please
make sure that you see that entire
playlist okay uh already in the playlist
we have developed about nine tutorials
I'll also give the playlist link now
what we are going to do quickly
I'm going to put this particular project
inside my GitHub so inside my GitHub
I've taken the entire copy of the
project I did not do the fork the reason
I did not do the fork because I need to
make some changes for the deployment in
Azure okay now what I will do all this
commit is basically happened now I'll go
ahead and open my Azure right now in
Azure we are going to create a web app
and then we are going to do the
deployment please note over here all the
step to step process that we are going
to follow this will be a continuous
deployment mechanism that we are going
to follow over here so first of all I
will go ahead and sign in so quickly go
ahead and sign in over here now after
you sign in it will ask for your
username and password please do that now
if you really want to deploy this in a
Azure webs app right and we'll do it
with the help of GitHub actions okay
automatically the GitHub action will
also get created now first of all I will
go ahead and create the resource okay
inside the resource I will be having web
app so we'll go ahead and create this
web app now once this web app is created
I'm going to get this information like
subscription I'm probably using right
now ineuron Azure so over here
subscription one group is there you have
to also create it if not whatever by
default value is coming you use that
we'll create a new Resource Group let's
say I'm going to write test group
regression okay so this will be my
Resource Group which will create the web
app inside this then I have to give my
web app name let's say I'm writing gem
prediction gem price prediction okay so
gem price prediction this will basically
be my entire URL because after the
deployment will be looking like gem
prediction dot azurewebsite.net we are
going to do this with GitHub action
please note all the step by step okay
then right now will be in code later on
I'll also show you Dockers okay I will
try to convert this entire project into
Docker and then show you then uh after
selecting you have to select the runtime
in runtime I will go ahead and select
python 3.8 and now I will just go ahead
and click on next after next it will ask
for the GitHub action settings okay now
GitHub action setting is very much
simple just go ahead and enable it and
make sure that you configure with your
GitHub account right now I have
configured with my GitHub account if you
want to configure just click on change
account and it'll ask you to configure
from here okay so in order to sign in it
will ask you for the authentication just
go ahead and do the authentication now
we'll select the organization it is
Krishna x06 because it is inside my
repository my repository name is student
ml project regression now see what will
happen okay so here I will write student
student ml project regression right so
this is uh this is my GitHub right I
guess student ml project regression so
I've selected this it will be the main
branch now the next thing we will do
just go ahead and create review plus
create okay now in reviewer plus create
these are all the information that I
have now finally I will just go ahead
and click on the create button now this
initialization this deployment will take
some time uh around couple of minutes so
we'll wait till this deployment will
happen but as soon as this happened
right if I reload this page right there
will be an automatic workflow that will
be created and this workflow is
basically getting created with the help
of GitHub action so once you create this
web app you know says the deployment is
in progress you know automatically
inside this GitHub right inside this
GitHub repository that GitHub folder
workflow folder will also get created so
we'll wait for some time you know and
we'll see that how this particular
folder will get created uh till the
deployment is basically happening okay
so let's wait for some time
so finally guys the deployment is
complete now now see what will happen
once the deployment happens I will go to
my GitHub page and I'll just reload it
automatically one additional folder has
got created which is called as GitHub
workflows okay now with respect to
GitHub workflows right if you probably
go ahead and click it and if you see
this file right this is the yaml file
that is got created
and it is basically saying that okay
build and deploy python app to Azure web
app right on push the main branch it is
basically considering the main branch
from where the code needs to be
dispatched to the server then it is
running on Ubuntu latest you know
basically in the server side if you
probably see these steps using actions
checkout you know this is basically
going to push the Repository
then you have what python version is
there then you have
starting with creating this particular V
and V environment like how we started
then the source it is basically
activating that then it is installing
all the dependencies then it is
deploying all the artifact of the
deployment job okay it is going inside
that inside this particular environment
then you can see this is basically my
web app URL which is it is picking up
from the secret key I'll show you the
secret key also which will be completely
unique then you have this entire steps
that is basically happening to deploy
and automatically it has created and
this is also super important which is
called as the Publix profile now how
this all information is basically coming
because we had already authenticated
right and if I probably go and see in
the settings and there will be an option
of secret and variable right so here you
will be seeing that this particular
secret variable has got created right in
the GitHub Azure app Service public
profile this name right and from this
entire information from this this
particular secret key whatever
information is basically present that is
basically read inside this particular
workflow see inside this vertical
profile like you require this app
service publish profile it is coming
from there you require this deploy to
web out whichever web URL is there that
is also reading from here it is also uh
reading some more informations with
respect to that now see
this is what is the GitHub action is
doing it is creating this entire EML
file which will have the necessary
configuration
now you can obviously see the
documentation page to understand each
and every step like what is it deploy
what is the steps and all but if you
really want me to make a dedicated video
on GitHub action step by step I'm happy
to make it just please make sure that
you make this particular video reach
1000 likes okay if you are able to do
that I'll start the series with respect
to GitHub action and I'll just turn it
to uh you know probably talk about this
step by step like what is this
particular parameter is basically saying
what is this completely detail you will
try to understand okay I'm kidding you
don't need to give even thousand likes
but I will make a dedicated GitHub
actions video okay uh it's just to say
you then only you basically like or
share my video with everyone okay but
don't worry if you don't like it also I
will make sure that I will try to create
a dedicated video on this but I really
wanted to show step by step how this is
automatically getting created
now as soon as uh this deployment
happened your deployment is complete
right you see in the GitHub action
in the GitHub action you will be able to
see
all this build and deployment has
actually happened in the build all the
steps like what is the setup job in the
yaml file it was run action checkout
right so what is basically happening
inside this it is syncing with this
repository it is getting the GitHub
version it is basically seeing this app
Runner right app Runner is what that
automatically deployment happens
whenever the changes are happening it is
initializing the repository it is doing
some steps like fetching repository and
all all the steps you'll be able to see
over here then set up python version
this is the second step with respect to
the deployment that has happened then we
went and created a virtual environment
installed all the dependencies with
respect to requirement.txtc
automatically all these things are so in
that ml file whatever is the steps
written right that entire steps is
basically happening line by line then we
upload the entire artifact in the form
of zip file inside the cloud okay
the Azure Cloud so this particular step
has also happened Post Run checkout so
here also you can see that
whatever cleanup is required after the
GitHub repository has been synced with
the cloud and then finally we complete
the job after build we basically do the
deployment now in deployment also you
can see setup objects download artifacts
and deploy towards your web app has
happened so if you really want to
understand that particular yaml file you
just need to see this step by step what
has happened okay and then you will be
able to get an idea but don't worry I'll
make a dedicated video about GitHub
action because to discuss about each and
everything right it will take around one
and a half hour
so uh this deployment has been done and
your url is also ready so I'll go and
click with respect to GitHub action C
when first time I ran it became wrong
because there was some problem but
automatically you'll be able to see that
this has been happen and this is what is
My URL now once I hit this URL you'll be
able to see the entire project is
available right now I will go and hit
some values okay automatically and this
is now running in Azure web okay 43 fair
this this okay and I'll submit it now
once I submitted it will basically do
the prediction and here you can see
prediction gemstone price is one six
eight four one again I've kept this
photo because again most of the credits
right with respect to the project
implementation goes to utkarsh right so
that is the reason I'm putting this
entire URL
now all you have to do is that take this
entire repository which I will be giving
you and
I'll give my repository only where it
has all the information with respect to
cash and then use Azure web to basically
do the deployment now once you do the
deployment once you test it the next
thing is that please delete this okay
please delete the deployment because
there may be some additional charges
just for practice purpose I've actually
created this so that you don't have to
worry about it okay so uh it has got
deleted now what I'll do is that I will
also delete this okay
so let me do one thing and here uh this
is delete okay so I'm just going to
click on delete and I have to just type
the app name that is Gem price
prediction you need to do this otherwise
you don't know what will happen but
automatically the money will get
deducted because you may require a
credit card over here but just to show
you how the deployment is happening I'm
basically showing you this step okay
perfect uh this was it from my side I
hope you like this particular video all
the information will be given in the
description but please let me know that
if you require
how to about GitHub actions and all I
will try to explain each and every
parameter to you so yes this was it for
my side I will see you all in the next
video please make sure that you
subscribe share with all your friends in
the next upcoming videos we will also be
deploying talking about different
different deployment techniques with app
Runner and all and then we'll go to ml
flow DVC where we'll discuss about CI CD
pipelines also so yes this was it from
my side I will see you all in the next
video thank you